The Guild Hall
Guild Hall?
Do you know about them?
I've heard of them,
but I didn't realize there's one here.
We try to avoid attention.
So if you don't know where to look,
the Guild tends to stay hidden.
This is your card.
And this is from Laojun.
For me?
It should help with your recovery.
Thank you.
Should I bring this back after I'm done?
Not necessary.
It should have more than enough on it.
Did Laojun tell you anything?
No, he didn't.
This card is also a pass to every guild hall.
We offer services for all Elfin who visit us.
Everyone?
You probably don't know how the Guild operates now.
Would you like me to explain?
If you have the time.
Of course, it's part of my job.
The Guild was founded by Laojun and two other deities.
There's one in each large human city.
We offer services for spirits.
Besides acting as an inn, like in old times,
it also provides financial support for living in the human world.
What's the catch?
Nothing.
Just follow the Guild's rules.
What are the rules?
Don't slay your own kind.
Don't reveal yourself to humans.
If you're willing to work with us,
you can reap even more benefits.
Are you gonna fight today, or not?!
Come on!
All right, I'll keep my mouth shut!
This is our practice field.
They're the ones we just met.
They are frequent visitors.
They can't live in the city because of their appearance.
Are they strong?
Yes.
Then how come they can't take a human form?
All spirits have their true form.
It's not about cultivation.
A human form is good only for blending in.
Even those who can't transform can find an expert.
They simply think it's below them to look human.
I see...
Who's the strongest between you guys?
I'd say I'm the weakest.
Then how come you're the hall manager?
I can make money.
How do you make money?
I sell these trees.
The lush vegetation here is your work, right?
Thank you.
Yes.
Trees born quickly from magic also die quickly.
But the trees whose growth I stimulate,
are capable of surviving.
Are trees that expensive?
High quality wood is extremely valuable.
Especially nowadays.
And moneymaking made you the boss?
Of course not.
Let's go a floor up.
There's one more floor?
Stand still.
This is the core of our hall.
You can see the location and data of every guild hall.
It's quite the spectical.
It's better at places with more bandwidth.
Space fluctuations...?
This isn't just a map, is it?
It's much more.
Every dot on the map represents a guild hall.
Besides being a marker,
each dot actually connects us to a hall.
You're saying these are all space points?
Exactly.
This is amazing.
Mr. Qianzhen.
Hey, Manager!
Showing them around?
The others are waiting.
You should hurry.
See ya later, little spirits!
Some people have a meet-up here.
He doesn't hate humans?
He can't tell who's human.
Anyone can use this place?
Yes.
Aren't there troublemakers?
Not for a long time.
You can see us over there.
The color of the upper dot shows the type of the hall.
Ours is gold, as we do mainly commerce.
The dots below stand for the resident spirits.
There's three of us here, including Tu Bei and me.
But also human assistants work in every hall.
How do others offer support if they can't earn money?
Resources are shared among halls.
Like capital, space, military force,
magic weapons and tools.
The hall manager can use them within their discretion.
If there are humans here,
why is it a rule that you can't reveal yourself to humans?
Many humans already know about our existence.
Like you, a confidant of Lord Xuanli.
But not every human can tolerate us.
It was better back then,
but since humans have gotten stronger, we've run into trouble.
After a few incidents, we established the current rules.
This is the best way to get along for now.
I don't really get it...
Why do you have to earn money in the first place?
Can't you just create gold or money?
It would wreck up the human financial world.
In the long run, it's best to follow their rules.
That means I should open an ice warehouse.
I'm gonna steal.
That's not making money...
Or you could do express deliveries.
Why not?
We're done with the introduction.
Do you want me to go into more detail?
Not for now.
Then let's grab some tea.
Won't you stay for lunch?
Sorry, my grandfather is waiting for me.
Today we can't.
It's all right.
This is for you.
For me?
Feel free to accept it.
It's from Laojun.
Didn't you promise anime merch to him?
Oh...
Should I take you to Shanxin's?
We're going to an anime con tomorrow.
I'm going to head back and help fix the shrine.
I'll see you in a couple days.
Hello?
Shanxin!
How did you know I'm here?
Yeah, I was about to head over.
Over there?!
'Sup, Gen.
Why are you here...?
I came for Xiaobai.
And Xiaohei, for Huang.
I'd rather go home...
What's wrong?
Mr. Fu and co. have left.
They went to the city.
They know how to behave.
They might be following Lord Xuanli.
Get off.
Unless you want to be attacked on the bus.
How can I help?
I need a sparing partner.
What are we doing here?
Conflict means an opening.
What if they see us?
Someone's here.
What do we do?
Can't we say we're just passing by?
We can not.
What are you doing here?
We came to help you!
He won't buy this...
Silence.
They're having fun.
Not both of them.
They're equally strong.
What are your thoughts, Polao?
One is just brute force.
The other is weak and powerless.
Who are you talking about, old man?
You and him.
Shut up, dumb toad!
This is bad...
Axian.
Let's go!
Don't cut me down...
Why are you in such a hurry?
He cut the space switch.
'Return home'?
It'll take a moment.
Stay alert.
If there's no more business,
may I leave now?
We came for the Sky Pearl.
Are you willing to part with it?
Just as I thought.
What do you mean?
The prizes of vow quests can be robbed.
I suppose you knew about this.
You get the wrong idea.
You say the Sky Pearl you have is not from Laojun?
I don't have any Sky Pearl.
Oh, no...
What's wrong?
He really doesn't have the Pearl.
So even you can be wrong?
Then it must be at the girl or the cat, surprisingly.
I was careless.
So may I leave now?
You shall keep us company for a few days.
You really have it wrong.
I can tell truth and lies apart.
It's useless to try to deny.
If you want to leave, you must defeat all of us.
Darn...
We won't trouble you any longer...
You don't trouble us.
But we may trouble you for a while.
Mission: Sky Pearl
Xiaobai!
Go forward and throw a grenade!
Sure!
Kitty Grenade
Xiaobai!
Are you all right?
Milk
See you out there.
Settings
Exit
What do you think?
You're awesome!
Didn't this just come out yesterday?
It's nothing.
I'm a pro after all.
I'm so tired...
What does it say?
Can I eat it?
This spirit space is quite comfortable.
Aren't you worried?
Why would I be?
For your comrades.
It makes no sense to worry.
I can't do anything.
But last time you beat us hard.
Because you guys are weak.
Oh.
Why is there a wall here?
Axian!
The space ends here!
Huh?
It ends abruptly?
It doesn't help us.
Aren't spirit spaces spherical?
Only natural, complete spaces are.
Really?
Since we're together in trouble now,
will you tell me now why you came here?
'River Fu' Spirit Elixir.
The day after a stable state is reached,
take one pill in the morning,
during the day and at the evening,
and you are cured.
P.S.!
Say hello to Wuxian for me.
This is written here.
I see.
Are you talking to Xiaohei?
Yeah.
Keep on dreaming, girl...
Xiaohei can understand me.
And Xiaohuang understands me.
Huang!
Why are acting so weird...
Can he understand a lot?
Be happy!
Smile!
Say meow!
Convinced yet?
I can't see a difference.
It's easy.
Be happy!
Be scared!
Convinced yet?
I'm not lying.
Not only he can understand me,
but I can understand him too.
How is this possible?
Xiaobai.
You can tell her that we can communicate,
but don't talk about spirits.
Okay.
What if it's true...?
I need to test it.
We're going to an anime con tomorrow.
Xiaobai is the cutest.
Oh, please, don't flatter me!
Amazing!
One more test!
You took Xiaohei to the bathroom,
but just stared at him and didn't say a word.
Believe it now?
I believe it.
Xiaohei also understands Bidiu.
He can translate for me.
Huang, you're useless.
Xiaohei says Xiaohuang says he's hungry.
You little glutton...
Dinner's ready!
I take it back, you're awesome.
Coming!
Moss, Axian and Tanjiu.
So you three came for the Sky Pearl too?
Are you mad at us, Lord Xuanli?
Not at all.
This might be your lucky day.
You need it for cultivation?
Yes.
Spirit force is scarce today.
Cultivation got much harder.
Sorry we left you alone.
Have you found it?
Not at this time.
It's hard to trace those riding a vehicle.
You said earlier that if we can find it,
you'd give it to us, correct?
Of course.
We've got no chance against you.
And I want them to be safe.
We appreciate it.
How can a robbery be that civilized?
They are all well-mannered.
Just now...
I thought I've heard you call him Xuanli.
Is it a problem?
No.
But he is not Xuanli.
I never said I was him.
Wow!
So many people!
Well, yeah.
It's the biggest anime convention in town.
I didn't know Xiaohei was interested in this.
It's rare for a cat.
I didn't want to stay there...
Anime Convention
I've sensed them.
This one, please.
Thanks for your purchase!
What did you buy?
Just a small gift.
Xiaobai?
Handsome guy.
"Gate of the Living" is now available at Sector B3.
An ID is required to make a purchase.
Do not use another person's name.
I'll go stand in line.
You go have fun.
I'll go with you.
You won't buy that.
We'll meet when I'm done.
I don't want you to go alone.
It's okay, Dad's here.
Hello, Mr. Shan!
I'm going now.
I'll call you.
Okay.
Feeling better, kitten?
Much better.
Why didn't you come back to the tower last time?
Leave the past alone...
What's the topic?
World politics.
What brings you here?
Shopping for Master Lao.
I want to do that too.
What a coincidence that we meet here!
I've heard your voice, so I came here.
You come here often?
Yes.
I can be myself here.
You like conventions?
Hi, can we make some pictures with you?
Sure.
Thank you!
You're welcome.
What character is he?
No idea, but he's so cute!
Oho...
You're yourself, huh?
Exactly.
I don't have to disguise myself here.
So it was Tanjiu who created your copies.
Only your spirit parts are here right now?
Yes.
Our real bodies are in a safe place.
We won't get hurt even if our copies are destroyed.
Of course, if we don't get them back,
we lose cultivation.
Judging by your appearance,
I assume you live among humans, right?
Yes.
We even have jobs.
You do?
We are...
Manhua artists!
They're late
with manuscripts
on cultivation days
I've never met a spirit who has such a job.
So you are in fact not Lord Xuanli?
That's right.
May I ask your family name?
Luo.
Wolverine?
Never mind...
Will we stay here forever?
Of course not.
I suppose you'd rather leave too.
So you have a plan.
If we join forces,
we can't defeat them,
but it's easy to escape.
These ones?
You think he'd like them?
We'd like these two, please.
Right away.
By the way...
Can you take this to Laojun?
You bought it for him?
Why don't you take it yourself?
I wanted to.
But Gen said the Blue Jade Disc can be used only once in a month.
Then I'll take it to him.
Isn't it Laojun's personal creation?
How come it can't be used more often?
The Disc is a first-rate magic tool for fixed-point teleportation.
I suppose the limit was set especially for you.
But why?
He doesn't want me to visit more often?
I cannot tell.
You should ask him next time.
Okay.
Your badges are packed.
This is it?
Yes.
It's quite crowded...
It won't be easy...
So what now?
Wait until they come out?
Have you found it?
Yes.
It's time you kept your promise.
Isn't it strange you can't see the other three?
Why do you ask?
Your closed eyes must be a facade.
I assumed you relied on spirit sense.
Haven't you noticed they already left?
None of you can leave this spirit space.
Don't be so sure about it.
None of you are space type.
How do you know we can't leave?
Jiuxian.
Stay here and keep watch.
I'll call Polao in.
So, what are all these humans doing here?
It's market day.
Polao.
Please come in for a minute.
Hm...
They are not here.
Impossible.
They don't possess such abilities.
Otherwise, why would they have stayed for so long?
They are going to look for the Sky Pearl.
Let's go.
Stay with me aruite yukou ishikoro wo kette
Stay with me - let's walk on, kicking pebbles as we go
Yukisaki wa kitto kimagure demo
Our destination may be whimsical
Hana no kaori wo ryoute ni
But with the scent of flowers in both hands
kore kara deau kimi e to
I’ll carry it to the you I’ve yet to meet
Wait for me hanashi wo shiyou kata wo narabete
Wait for me — let’s talk, side by side
Hajimemashite wa gikochinaku temo
Even if our first “hello” is a little awkward
Mochiyotta hako aketara
When we open the boxes we’ve brought
Tsumekon da yume wo wakeaou
Let’s share the dreams we’ve packed inside
Mata ashita tte atarimae ni kawaseru hibi ga
The days when we can casually say “See you tomorrow”
Itoshikute hakanasugite
Are so precious and so fleeting
Omoi wa kitto kienai
Those feelings will never fade away
Sora wo nagareru kumo ni wa oitsukenai kedo
We can’t catch up to the clouds drifting across the sky
Ame ni natte hana wo tsukete kitto boku wo yonderu
But they’ll turn to rain, bloom into flowers
Kitto boku wo yonderu
And surely, they’re calling out to me